Inspired by true events
The Birdcatcher is a drama, thriller, war film directed by Ross Clarke.
Norway, 1942, during World War II.
After being separated from her family, Esther, a young Jewish girl from Trondheim, arrives at an
isolated farm where she must assume a new identity in order to survive the Nazi persecution.
Esther, played by Sarah-Sofie Boussnina.
Aksel, played by Arthur Hakalahti.
Johann, played by Jakob Cedergren.
Anna, played by Laura Birn.
Fred, played by Johannes Bah Kuhnke.
Herman, played by August Diehl.
The Birdcatcher is a 2019 film directed by British film-maker
Ross Clarke and written by Trond Morten Kristensen.
Set in Nazi-occupied Norway, supposedly based on a composite of real cases, it concerns
Esther, a Jewish girl, who lives disguised as a boy on a Norwegian farm.
Danish actrees Sarah-Sofie Boussnina plays Esther, Jakob Cedergren
plays farmer and Norwegian collaborationist Johann.
His wife Anna (Laura Birn) is secretly in an affair
with a German officer (August Diehl).
The film explores themes of holocaust (shoah), world war ii, jew
persecution, based on true story, nazi collaborationism.
The tone is emotional and intense.